<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://phomarkon.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://phomarkon.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-07-07T05:02:12+00:00</updated><id>https://phomarkon.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Phongsakon Mark Konrad</title><subtitle>Personal website of Phongsakon Mark Konrad - Future Researcher with Entrepreneurial Spirit. Research Assistant at SDU, passionate about machine learning and deep learning. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome</title><link href="https://phomarkon.github.io/blog/2025/welcome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome"/><published>2025-07-06T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-06T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://phomarkon.github.io/blog/2025/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://phomarkon.github.io/blog/2025/welcome/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome. You might notice this is the only post here. While I would love to blog more, I’m a firm believer that you can do anything, but not everything. For that reason, I’ve decided to put my main focus on my research activities for now.</p> <p>Below a text from my intro:</p> <blockquote> <p>My path to research has been anything but direct. I moved from Thailand to Germany as a kid, spent four years in the German Navy, and later co-founded two startups after coming to Denmark. What those experiences taught me is that my real drive isn’t building a business, but understanding how things learn and think. The questions that matter to me are academic ones.</p> <p>So now, I’m a software engineering undergraduate at the University of Southern Denmark, working as a research assistant with Associate Professor Serkan Ayvaz, who thankfully gives me the freedom to chase these ideas.</p> <p>I’m trying to absorb as much as I can across the field before a PhD. I’m interested in almost everything, but I can feel a definite pull. I’m drifting away from straightforward computer vision and more towards the cognitive and philosophical foundations of our work. My interest in psychology and neuroscience keeps leading me back to questions of thinking, reasoning, and what it even means for a model to be trustworthy.</p> <p>The idea that really grips me is the internal life of these models. The concept of ‘model dreaming’—of a model learning from its own internally generated reality—feels important. I suspect the next breakthroughs won’t just come from more data or bigger models, but from getting closer to these foundational principles of cognition. That’s the territory I want to spend my career exploring, starting with a PhD.</p> </blockquote> <h3 id="so-what-is-this-site-far-future">So, What Is This Site (Far Future)?</h3> <p>This blog will be a reflection of that journey. It will likely be a mix of half-formed ideas, notes on papers that I find compelling, updates on my own research, and explorations into the cognitive side of AI. I find it helpful to write things down to clarify my own thinking.</p> <p>If you’re also wrestling with these kinds of ideas or just find them interesting, I’d be happy to connect.</p> <ul> <li>📧 Email: <a href="mailto:phongsakon@outlook.dk">phongsakon@outlook.dk</a></li> <li>💼 LinkedIn: <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/phongsakonmarkkonrad">linkedin.com/in/phongsakonmarkkonrad</a></li> </ul> <p>This site is, and will likely always be, a work in progress—much like my own understanding. Thanks for stopping by.</p> <hr/> <p><em>P.S. - You might see “early sleeper” listed as a skill of mine. I’m only half-joking. The kinds of problems I want to work on require a well-rested brain.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal"/><category term="welcome"/><category term="introduction"/><category term="personal"/><category term="research"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few words on what this place is for.]]></summary></entry></feed>